glasses.com 2019-03-06

# Privacy Policy | Glasses.com® | Free Shipping

* * *

For more information on Interest-based Advertising and your choices regarding it, click here

This website is managed by Luxottica Retail North America Inc. 4000 Luxottica Place, Mason, Ohio 45040, a subsidiary of Luxottica Group S.p.A. ("Luxottica"), and the privacy and security measures applicable to this website are designed with the strictest security in mind, so any personal information that you provide via this website is used only for the purposes outlined herein. This privacy policy tells you how Luxottica and its subsidiaries collect and use your personal information, who they share it with and how you can access, change and remove your information. When used in this policy, depending on the context, "we," "our" and "us" refers to Luxottica and its affiliates, individually and collectively. 

Effective 2/26/2019 

_**Here are the basics:**_

**We will treat your information the same way we'd treat our own. We won’t sell your information, we won’t use your information to spam you to death, and most importantly, we will do everything we can to make sure your information is secure. Additionally, you can unsubscribe at any time—no hard feelings. If that was** _**too**_ **basic, keep reading for the page-turning legal version!**

**So what’s in this Privacy Policy?**

This policy describes the personal information we at glasses.com collect, why we collect it, and how we use it. This policy also describes your options concerning how we collect and use your information. 

If our information practices change in the future, don’t worry—we will notify you by posting the policy changes directly to this web page _before_ any changes are implemented. 

At glasses.com, we value you and respect your privacy, that is why we only collect your information for three purposes: 1) to improve your shopping experience; 2) to process your order (including verification of your prescription, if necessary and with your authorization); and 3) to keep you up-to-date regarding optical goods, ocular health, and even some awesome promotions. Don’t worry, we will maintain and use your information responsibly. We promise. And we won't sell, rent, or loan any of your information to any third party. In other words, that junk mail you just got was _not_ because of us! 

**What kind of information does glasses.com collect?**

We collect personal information that you provide (such as any pictures or videos you upload or use, name, mailing address, phone number, email address, credit card number, patient’s name (if different from your own), eyeglass prescription, and the name and phone number of the eye care provider) when placing an order, registering with us, or participating in a promotion. We also maintain a record of your past purchases. Our information systems are also fully integrated which means after your first order, regardless of _how_ you ordered (phone, web, etc.), we can look you up in a snap. 

Currently, we also use third-party service providers to track and analyze non-personally identifiable information about our visitors and customers. We use this information to improve our site and plan for technical improvements. This information may also be used by our third party service providers to direct advertising content on other web sites. For more information about this type of advertising visit [ www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) . We reserve the right to publish non-personally identifiable summary information regarding our website visitors for promotional purposes and as a representative audience for advertisers. Please note that this is _not_ personal information, it only consists of general summaries of the activities of our visitors and customers. 

**How does glasses.com use my information?**

First, we use your personal information to fulfill your orders. Second, we use it to confirm your order (or contact you if we have any questions regarding your order). Third, we may contact you (either directly or through a service provider bound by strict confidentiality) to help us learn more about your shopping preferences so that we may better serve you. Fourth, we may use your information to help us better improve our site design and your shopping experience. Finally, we may send you notices about our products, services, contests, surveys and promotions or news about eyeglasses or contact lenses, optical goods, or ocular health. 

**Does glasses.com share my information with third parties?**

We do not share your personal information with any third or outside party, except to verify your prescription, as explained in the next paragraph. If you opt to receive no commercial email from us, we will add your email address to a “do not mail” list, which may be given to trusted outside parties in order to ensure your email address is excluded from any third-party email distribution. We do not sell, rent or loan any information about you to any third parties. 

PLEASE NOTE: On all orders placed, we do attempt to verify or obtain a copy of your eyeglass prescription from the eye care provider that you designate. This information is held under the same strict confidentiality standards as described above and in accordance with all applicable laws. 

**How do I access my information? How do I update my information?**

After you register, you can access your account online by clicking the “My Account” link at the top of any of the pages on [www.glasses.com](http://www.glasses.com/). Here you can edit your billing, shipping, email preferences, login information and password settings. You can also make these changes by calling us at 1-800 GLASSES (1-800-452-7737) to speak with a Customer Service Representative. 

**How do I remove my information from email, postal mailing and telephone lists?**

To change your email preferences, click the “My Account” link and then click “Account Settings & Password.” You can also call one of our Customer Service Representatives at 1-800 GLASSES (1-800-452-7737). If you prefer not to receive postal mail, please let us know by sending us an email to [info@glasses.com](mailto:info@glasses.com) or give us a call at 1-800 GLASSES (1-800-452-7737). 

PLEASE NOTE: Requests to be removed from the postal mail list may take up to 6-8 weeks to process. Sorry about that. Also, if you remove your name and address from our email or postal mailing lists, we will maintain your name in a “do not mail” file to ensure that we can honor your request. 

When you make a purchase, we will send you an email to confirm your order, and send an email when your order is shipped. We may also need to contact you via phone, postal mail or email if we have other questions regarding your order. 

**How does glasses.com protect my child’s privacy?**

We take children’s safety seriously. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, we will never request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. 

If we are aware or learn that a subscriber is under the age of 13 and has registered without prior verifiable parental consent, we will remove his or her personally identifiable registration information from our files. 

**What about links to other Internet sites and services?**

We may maintain links to other websites that are not under our control. These websites have their own policies regarding privacy, which you should review before visiting them. We have no responsibility for linked websites and provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our customers. 

**How does glasses.com make sure my order information is secure?**

Protecting your order information is a priority for us. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect the security of your online order information. More than 90% of Fortune 500 companies use SSL security to protect their sensitive personal and financial information, so you know it’s “the good stuff.” 

To check the security of your connection, look at the lower corner of your browser window after accessing the server. If you see an unbroken key or a closed lock (depending on your browser), the SSL is active and the server is secure. You can also double-check by looking at the URL line of your browser. When assessing a secure server, the first characters of the site address will change from “http://” to “https://”. 

When you use our ordering page you can be assured that your sensitive personal information and financial transactions with us are encrypted, safe, and secure. 

**Does glasses.com use adware or spyware?** **What is adware? What is spyware?**

Adware is software that is installed on your computer that can, for example, create pop-up advertisements or cause your browser to be redirected to other websites. We do not participate in or use third-party services that use adware. We believe this type of advertising could be confusing for some customers. We work to ensure that these third-party adware services do not function on our website. 

Spyware is software that is installed on your computer that can, for example, record and transmit information regarding the websites you visit or record and transmit your keystrokes to a third party. In addition to being super creepy, we wouldn’t want that software used on us. So we don’t want it used on you. Spyware, like adware, is often installed without the knowledge of the person using the computer. We do not use spyware and we work to ensure that spyware does not function on our website either. 

**What are cookies? How does glasses.com use cookies on its site?**

Some cookies are round, delicious treats—best served hot, right out of the oven. These are not the cookies we use. The cookies we use are small files stored on your computer's hard drive that contain information that is used to track the pages of the sites you've visited. 

We use cookies to improve your shopping experience. When you visit our website, your cookie helps us keep track of your order as you shop at our site. If you are a registered customer, your cookie allows us to recognize you when you return to our site and provides you with access to your account information. If you register with or order from us, we also use cookies to maintain information about your use of our website in a manner that identifies you as a customer. This information helps us serve you better by improving our site design, as well as our services, contests, surveys and promotions. 

Even though we would share our cookies with you, you don’t need to share your cookies with us. Just turn them off in your web browser. However, if you turn your cookies off, we will not be able to track your order, enable your purchase from our site, or recognize you as a registered user to allow you access to your account information. 

**Interest-based Advertising and Choice**

We may engage and work with service providers and other third parties to serve advertisements on the service and/or on third-party services. Some of these ads may be tailored to your interests based on your browsing of the service and elsewhere on the Internet, sometimes referred to as “interest-based advertising” and “online behavioral advertising” (“Interest-based Advertising”), which may include sending you an ad on a third-party service after you have left the service (i.e., “retargeting”).   
You may choose whether to receive some Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt-outs. Some of the advertisers and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and third parties may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>, and <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices> for information on the DAA’s opt-out program for mobile apps.   
Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt-out options for their members, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads.   
Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit these opt-out webpages, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different device or web browser or use a non-browser-based method of access (e.g., mobile app), your NAI / DAA browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective. We support the ad industry’s 2009 Self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising (<https://www.iab.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf>) and expect that ad networks we directly engages to serve you Interest-based Advertising will do so as well, though we cannot guarantee their compliance. We are not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs. 

**Tracking across time and technologies disclosure:**

Some information about your use of the service and certain third-party services may be collected using tracking technologies across time and services and used by us and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the service and certain third-party services.
